TRUONG KHUONG

khuongtnq@gmail.com | 0987 049 314 My portfolio: khuongtnq.github.io/myresume/

Brief introduction

Hi! I'm a software engineer.

I've been an engineer professionally for 4 years, worked as backend engineer at 2 startups, along with a few side projects.

I have considerable experience in web development. I can easily adapt to changes and I am willing to learn. Besides, I have always wanted to work in the startup company and spent so much time to read about this industry. With my knowledge and enthusiasm, I think I can do well in this position.

Education

University Of Information Technology Bachelor of Computer Science

Sept 2014 - May 2018

• Courses: OOP in C++, Compilers, Algorithms, Operating Systems, Data Structures

Skills

Languages: Ruby, Java, Javascript

Technologies: React.js, Ruby on Rails, Postgresql, AWS, Git, Docker

Exposure: AWS, Linux, MacOs, Kafka, Elasticsearch

Professional Experience

Deliveree On-Demand Logistics

July 2019 – Present

 $Software\ Engineering-Production\ Team-Product\ Full\ Truck\ Load$

July 2019 – Dec 2020

- Implemented data and logic from APIs to UI components React.js in webapp
- Designed and implemented data models for business logic that integrated with model, APIs and thoroughly tested using unit or integration tests
- Reduce the bug Jira by 25% on 2 months, apply scrum on project team by educating and implementing
- Wrote scripts to correct data on productions about relation bookings

Backend Engineering - Cargo Team - Product Partial Truck Load

Dec 2020 - Present

- A product solution for list smaller deliveries and get competitive bids and best prices.
- Using an event driven architecture Kafka for the interactions between key modules through topic messages (bundling engine, FTL and PTL platform)
- Implemented Elasticsearch monitoring and search my booking of customer, faster about 15% than before.
- Write helper functions and using them as much as possible to avoid code repetitions.

Revollet Browser-based crypto wallet

Backend Engineering

April 2018 – July 2019

- A web applications solution for crypto exchange, money remittance, prepaid cards and crypto trading platforms.
- Reduced the bouncing rate by 10%, using B2B API security to crypto exchange.
- Built a stock prediction REST API to predict the stock performance of any given company. The feature to help stock traders/investors to understand trend and decide on investments.
- Trained the model using a node tree base on MongoDB data, liner regression.

Freelance Engineer

Software Engineering

After working as a full-time engineer for a while, I wanted to give freelancing a try.

- Project allows customer to discover and book online with salons, spas and nails. Booking through the Webapp services.
- Facilitated module sessions with the implementation team to define the solution for website services nail spa

Honors and Awards

- We code challenge (encourage prize Dec 2015)
- UIT hackathon (encourage prize team Nov 2016)

Information

• LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/khuong-truong-96a85015b/

Github: https://github.com/khuongtnq
GitLab: https://github.com/khuongtnq

 $\bullet \ Skype: khuontnq@gmail.com$